CODY RODRIGUEZ

209-710-7008 cody.rod93@gmail.com https://www.codyrod.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/codyrodriguez-716635194/

I am a software engineer with industry experience building web applications in the E-commerce and healthcare sectors. My experience includes a diverse set of positions and codebases. I have held titles such as Fullstack, Frontend, and mobile developer at different career stages. I specialize in JavaScript/Typescript and have professional experience working with Angular, React, Next JS, Remix, and Node JS. I have hobby experience with Go, Python(Django), & React Native.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sr. Software Engineer (Full Stack) IQVIA - DMD

December 2022 - Present

Develop & upgrade internal applications to support in-house healthcare audience data.

- Standardized docker virtualized local environment development.
- Document React & Typescript standards and code conventions across internal codebases.
- Stabilize email authentication applications to promote use among internal employees.

Front End Developer AVB Marketing June 2021 - December 2022

Delivered features and support for an E-commerce application. This application allows AVB Members to

sell their products directly to consumers. Upgraded UI for advance tier members.

- Give buying customers a multitude of options by implementing multiple third-party payment systems.
- Enhanced the capture of crucial customer trends for analytics, by implementing Facebook Conversion API.

Knowledge leveraged: Next JS, React JS, Typescript, Node JS, Material UI.

Programmer Analyst E&J Gallo Winery October 2018 - June 2021

Developed marketing websites built on Angular and headless Drupal. Built out email templates in Salesforce Marketing Cloud. Developed and maintained Ionic Angular Clover Point of Sale application. Developed lambda functions for CRON jobs in AWS.

- Created wine club dashboard UI in core websites for tasting members.
- Selected to receive corporate I.T Teamwork award for 2020.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Programmer Analyst E&J Gallo Winery

October 2018 - June 2021 (continued)

 Implemented price override feature to allow tasting room employees to set wine product prices for promo or customer service exemptions in the Point of Sale app.

Knowledge leveraged: Angular, Typescript, SCSS, Ionic, Node JS, Salesforce Marketing Cloud, AWS.

Software Developer I
Stanislaus County
October 2016 - October 2018

Created and maintained databases in the MSSQL server, created any necessary queries and reports staff might need. Along with basic troubleshooting support.

- Implemented full-stack Express JS web app by rewriting legacy ColdFusion app. This app was used by county employees to submit monitor water testing samples.
- Incorporated state-mandated software updates to county employees in a given timeframe.
- Increased leadership productivity by developing desktop app to organize and maintain county agenda items and related documents.

Knowledge leveraged: Express JS, JQuery, SQL, MS Access.

React Developer
Jamestown Apps
September 2016 - October 2016

As a team member, developed dashboard pages for a water monitoring nonprofit.

Knowledge leveraged: React JS, CSS

EDUCATION

B.S Computer Science

California State University Stanislaus

A.S Computer Science

Merced College